# **EMILY HANNAN**

### **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

**■** emilyhannan@gmail.com

**4** 250.891.8411

in linkedin.com/in/emilyhannan github.com/hannan-emily

http://ehannan.herokuapp.com

## **Technical Summary**

Full Stack Web Developer of immersive applications with creative, responsive designs. I'm a proactive, team centered developer with over 5 years experience as a designer with agency, retail and media/publishing experience. A hybrid developer and designer who works well in broader multi-disciplinary teams. I develop responsive, design-forward web applications with delightful twists.

Languages JavaScript, Python, SQL, HTML 5, CSS, CSS Grid

Frameworks Express, Node.js, Django

 Libraries
 React, Redux, jQuery, Materialize, Bootstrap

 Databases
 PostgreSQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose

 Design
 Web Fonts, Responsive UI Design, Photoshop

Other AJAX, Axios, Git, GitHub, Heroku, RESTful Web Services, HTML Canvas

## Education

Web Development Immersive

General Assembly, 2018 Seattle, WA

Master of Fine Arts

Cranbrook Academy of Art, 2012

Bloomfield Hills, MI

**Bachelor of Fine Arts** 

University of Washington, 2010

Seattle, WA

## **Project Highlights**

#### Mood Tracker GROUP

Python, Django, Materialize Chart your mood by analysing your selfies! A responsive, object oriented design app in Python/Django, we utilized the Amazon Rekognition machine learning API, Charts, is and Materialize to generate an image-rich tracker of each user's mood, by their selfies. I developed all front end components in Django & Materialize, with a major emphasis on clean, responsive UI. Acted as GitMaster and Project Manager to ensure our product met the required standards.

#### Apocalyprep GROUP

React, Redux, MongoDB, Mongoose NOAA API, React-Materialize A comprehensive, real time emergency prep app. Built as a responsive, image-rich application in React with Redux. I built the MongoDB schema, Mongoose routing and all front end styling including implementing React-Materialize. App integrated the NOAA API. I compiled custom emergency prep content from multiple Canadian and US disaster relief agencies, and built a seeder object to populate a master "supply list" database. I acted as the Project Manager.

## PNW Overland INDIVIDUAL

Node.js, EJS, Express, PostgreSQL, JavaScript An interactive Node is app, serving as an exploration guide to Pacific Northwest backcountry offroading trails. Featuring interactive custom Google Map API calls, responsive imagery and embedded auto-play video. The app integrates Google Map APIs, curated dash cam videos, community guides and user functionality to save favourite trails and leave notes for other users. Pair programmed with team members to solve database and routing challenges.

## Chasing Carmen SanDiego

INDIVIDUAL HTML5 Canvas, JavaScript, jQuery A delightfully fun HTML5 Canvas trivia based game, pitting two users against that international thief, Carmen SanDiego. I designed custom graphics and UI elements for a responsive user experience. Players interact with witnesses as canvas obstacles, and if they answer enough questions right - they've found Carmen!

## Experience

#### Web Development Immersive

General Assembly, Seattle, WA

Jan - April 2018

A 3-month, 60+ hrs/week, project-based web development accelerator. Educated in popular web technologies, database development, CRUD, RESTful routing, responsive UI design, Git and version control. Practiced pair-programming, Agile development, rapid prototyping and peer code review.

#### **Graphic Designer**

Black Press, Saanich, BC

Oct 2017 - Jan 2018

Responsible for layout, graphics and advertising design for a twice weekly newspaper. Managed client deliverables, working with external clients and internal stakeholders, including editorial, sales and design teams. Designed 20+ digital advertising graphics for responsive web and mobile applications per week. Content strategy and design for a range of retail, ecommerce, outdoor sports, grocery and food service clients.

## **Graphic Designer**

May - Oct 2017

Media One, Victoria, BC

UX/UI design, planning and strategy for a wide range of clients, including a marine suspensions seating manufacturer, food delivery app, fishing charter tours, and a restaurant management app. Produced client deliverables, working with external clients and coordinating production with internal web developer and video production team. Digital advertising graphic design, optimized for Google Adword placement. Campaign asset design for desktop, mobile, print and industry conference deliverables.

#### Co-Founder

May 2016 - May 2017

The Little Red Backpack, Victoria, BC

Founded a Social Media Consulting Company. Content graphic design, brand strategy and logo design. Designed content strategy development plans, including content maps, brand imaging guidelines and community response plans.

### Marketing Coordinator & Designer July 2015 - May 2017

Capital Iron, Victoria, BC

Sole advertising designer for large corporate retailer. Managed and produced all design deliverables and CMS, managed external and internal clients and integrated SEO keywords in digital and print assets. Annual advertising budget over \$300,000 with over one million in annual sales. Creative strategy planning and graphic design for web, mobile and print media. Primary social media and community manager.